Guide to the California Rural Legal Assistance, Inc. records M0750
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
- Record Group 5. Advocacy, circa 1967-1998
  - Series 1. Individual Attorney Files
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, CRLA history files; includes mostly "Lit-Directors" conference files and clippings (29 folders), circa 1982-1992 (Carton 368)
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, working files on the IRCA; includes promotional material, amendments, and correspondence related to the IRCA and immigration (10 folders), circa 1980-1990 (Box 244)
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, working files on Special Agricultural Workers (SAWS) and immigration; includes SAWS and RAWS (Replacement Agricultural Workers) correspondence, conference materials, alien eligibility research, and selective service documents (13 folders), circa 1980-1990 (Box 245)
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, working files; includes immigration research materials, correspondence, clippings, committee minutes; topics include naturalization, eligibility, INS proposals, day laborers, and compliance (32 folders), circa 1980-1990 (Carton 246)
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, working files on DeHaro v. City of St. Helena (Calif.), and alienage as it relates to labor issues; record types include research documents, correspondence, pleadings, and clippings (10 folders), circa 1980-1990 (Box 247)
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, working files; includes pleadings from various cases, such as: Catholic Social Services (CSS) v. Meese, various class action approval forms, United Farm Workers (UFW) v. INS, and the appeals documents from Zambrano v. INS (7 folders), circa 1980-1990 (Box 248)
    - Stephen Rosenbaum, working files, administrative and correspondence; includes training materials, poverty-law seminar papers, outreach, and research on negotiations and attorney's fees, and correspondence (12 folders), circa 1980-1990 (Box 249)
    - Tony White, administrative and LSC files (Legal Service Corporation); includes LSC issues and regulations files, monitoring, annual progress reports, procedures and instructions files, district office notes and guidelines, intake directions, and general research (26 folders), circa 1984-1990 (Box 320)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged A-B; topics include action board documents, attorneys' fees, and AWPA through bankruptcy, breach of fiduciary duty, and Brown v. The Artery Organization; record types include pleadings, memos, clippings, and research documents (38 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Carton 218)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged A-C; topics include access to public records research through CHAIN (California housing action and information network) documents; record types include clippings, memos and correspondence, pleadings, and research (45 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Carton 215)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged B-C; topics include CHFA and child discrimination (4 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Box 216)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged and includes topics that start with the letter C; topics include California farm labor through CEQA updates and CFR federal preferences (14 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Box 219)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged C-D; topics include claim of exemption through disclosure of social services; record types include research, memos, correspondence, pleadings, and clippings (49 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Carton 217)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged D-E; topics include displacement, DMV records, discrimination, EDD, employee housing and rights, equal protection, ethics, and eviction; record types include pleadings, correspondence, research documents, and clippings (43 folders) (Carton 303)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged E-F; topics include eviction issues through First Amendment issues; record types include research documents, memos, pleadings, clippings, motions, injunctions, and correspondence (55 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Carton 214)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged F-H; topics include Gilroy development, good cause evictions, growth management, and habitability; record types include, mostly pleadings, research documents, correspondence and notes (40 folders), circa 1985-1990 (Carton 276)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged and includes topics that start with the letter H; topics mostly include HUS housing, and housing issues; includes pleadings, research, memos and related correspondence (24 folders), circa 1981-1994 (Carton 242)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged and includes topics that start with the letter H; topics mostly include housing issues and homelessness; also includes public health and handicapped issues research; record types include inter-office memos, pleadings, clippings, correspondence, and research (51folders), circa 1985-1994 (Carton 241)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged I-L; topics include illegal leases, implied rights, labor issues, and late fees; record types include research documents, correspondence, pleadings, and notes (54 folders), circa 1985-1995 (Carton 277)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged and includes topics that start with the letter P; topics mostly include public housing; record types include pleadings, correspondence, research documents, and clippings (19 folders), circa 1981-1991 (Box 243)
    - Tony White, working files, alphabetically arranged R-S; topics include retaliation and rental research through Santa Clara County and San Francisco evictions (and Section 8 issues)(38 folders), circa 1980-1995 (Carton 240)
    - Tony White, mixed case files; includes the Christopher Ranch case, McFarland Water, Rancho Salinas, and housing cases; record types include pleadings, correspondence, notes, and research (16 folders), circa 1985-1990 (Box 299)
    - Tony White, mixed files; includes memos, notes, clippings (1 folder), circa 1981-1984 (Half-box 387)
  - Series 2. Legislation
    - Auto Insurance legislation; Senate and Assembly Bills related to motor vehicle reparations; includes copies of bills and amended bills, reports, notes, memos, correspondence (8 folders), 1973-1974 (Box 372)
    - ACR 74; correspondence and notes concerning legislation that required a comprehensive study to determine the language needs of non-English speaking citizens at every step of the judicial process, 1973-1975 (Carton 266, Folders 17-19)
    - Consumer rights legislation; topics include UCCC (United Consumer Credit Code) and consumer credit warranties (50 folders), circa 1970-1975 (Carton 319)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes Assembly and Senate Bills (27 folders), 1972-1974 (Carton 366)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes Assembly Bills (47 folders), 1973-1974 (Carton 362)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes United Consumer Credit Code (UCCC), and model Consumer Credit Act files and redrafts, copies of Senate Bills, correspondence, and research (35 folders), circa 1972-1975 (Carton 322)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on credit life and disability, consumer finance, and finance companies (42 folders), circa 1975 (Carton 383)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes notes and correspondence on credit reporting (5 folders), circa 1975 (Box 384)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes Senate and Assembly Bills (66 folders), 1971-1980 (Carton 302)
    - Consumer rights legislation; includes United Consumer Credit Code (UCCC), and other miscellaneous consumer related Senate Bills (44 folders), circa 1970-1980 (Carton 321)
    - Correspondence; includes miscellaneous incoming and outgoing letters and memos regarding legislation and civil rights issues (10 folders), circa 1979-1980, 1981 (Box 323)
    - Correspondence; includes regarding housing issues in legislation (5 folders), circa 1979-1980 (Box 324)
    - Education legislation; includes Assembly bills (37 folders), 1972 (Carton 198)
    - Education legislation; includes Assembly and Senate Bills (80 folders), circa 1970-1975 (Carton 363)
    - Education legislation; includes Assembly and Senate bills (48 folders), circa 1970-1979 (Carton 257)
    - Education legislation; includes Assembly and Senate bills (65 folders), circa 1970-1979 (Carton 258)
    - Education legislation; includes Assembly and Senate bills (109 folders), circa 1970-1979 (Carton 259)
    - Education legislation; includes Assembly and Senate bills (41 folders), circa 1970-1979 (Box 310)
    - Employment legislation; includes Senate bills (17 folders), 1973-1974 (Box 252)
    - Employment legislation; includes Senate and Assembly Bills (31 folders), circa 1973-1985 (Carton 326)
    - Ex-offender legislation; includes Assembly and Senate Bills (26 folders), circa 1970-1975 (Carton 367)
    - Finance legislation; includes topics such as financial responsibility and no fault insurance (43 folders), circa 1970-1980 (Carton 327)
    - Health issues legislation; includes Senate and Assembly bills (46 folders), circa 1978 (Carton 359)
    - Healthcare legislation; includes notes, reports, correspondence, and other material related to the state of California's efforts to establish universal health care (4 folders), circa 1990 (Box 354)
    - Legislation (numerical); includes Assembly bills: AB48-AB2699 (54 folders), 1971 (Carton 199)
    - Legislation (numerical); includes Assembly and Senate bills: AB2719-AB3057; ACA39-AJR125; SB10-SB1627; SCR124 (54 folders), 1971 (Carton 250)
    - Legislation (numerical); includes Senate bills: SB26-SB1454, SCR4; also legislation related to minority representation on juries (41 folders), 1972 (Carton 196)
    - Legislation (numerical); includes Assembly and Senate bills: AB101-AB3770; ACA13-ACA60; AJR89; ACR192; SB80-SB2246; SJR9; SCA3 (66 folders), 1973-1974 (Carton 251)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 9-234, Assembly Constitutional Amendment 45, and Senate Bills 1493, 1419, and 1420; includes notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on labor relations, prisons, insurance, taxation, civil servants, real estate, housing, MediCal, courts, and other matters (56 folders), circa 1972 (Carton 300)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 510-891; also notes and correspondence on proposed legislation involving insurance, contracts, courts, zoning, real estate, and other matters (47 folders), 1979-1980 (Carton 269)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 910-2179; also notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on insurance, real estate, courts, land use, elections, development, taxation, contracts, public employment, housing, cities, and other matters (66 folders), 1979-1980 (Carton 283)
    - Mixed legislation; includes notes and correspondence on proposed assembly and senate bills on migrant education, workmen's comp, child care, voter registration, job training, labor relations, and other matters (75 folders), circa 1980 (Carton 350)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 2200-2753; also notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on real estate, insurance, courts, and other matters (28 folders), 1979-1980 (Box 284)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 2784-3439, Assembly Constitutional Amendments 5-78, and other assembly legislation; also notes and correspondence on proposed legislation, constitutional amendments, resolution, and other types of legislation on real estate, elections, housing, loans, contracts, insurance, taxation, energy conservation, and other matters (51 folders), 1979-1980 (Carton 285)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 44-2856, Assembly Constitutional Amendments 5-54, Assembly Concurrent Resolutions 23-44, Assembly Joint Resolutions 8-31, House Resolution 13, and Senate Bills 22-584; includes notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on benefits eligibility, housing, child care, welfare eligibility, English as the official state language, the voting rights act, bilingual education, and other matters (100 folders) (Carton 344)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills 2254-3830, Assembly Constitutional Amendments 68 and 84, and Assembly Concurrent Resolutions 33, 61, and 100; includes notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on unemployment, courts, insurance, housing, discrimination, real estate, and other matters (94 folders) (Carton 351)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Senate Bills 2-1158, other state legislation; includes notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on education, budget, housing, labor, and other matters (35 folders) (Carton 304)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Senate Bills 1026-2037, Senate Constitutional Amendments 4-44, Senate Concurrent Resolutions 26, 29, 58, and Department of Housing and Community Development Budget; includes notes and correspondence on proposed legislation and constitutional amendments regarding real estate, contracts, courts, standards of affordable housing, loan interest rates, and other matters (70 folders), 1979-1980 (Carton 280)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Senate Bills 9-997; also notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on domestic violence, legal proceedings, insurance, courts, real estate, public transportation, and other matters (75 folders), 1979-1980 (Carton 281)
    - Mixed legislation; Senate Bills 1309-2224, Senate Constitutional Amendments 40-66, Senate Concurrent Resolution 75; also notes and correspondence on proposed legislation on courts, the budget, unemployment compensation, insurance, real estate, housing, welfare, and other matters (67 folders), 1978-1979 (Carton 282)
    - Mixed legislation; includes 1979 legislative report, Assembly and Senate session material (4 folders), 1979-1982 (Box 325)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills (49 folders), circa 1977-1978 (Carton 328)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Senate Bills (66 folders), circa 1977-1978 (Carton 329)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills from the 1975-1976 session, AB 1-899, a large portion of records dealing with the right to vote, labor commissioners' enforcement of labor laws, and employer practices regarding arrest records (30 folders) (Carton 360)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills from the 1977-1978 session, AB 1000-2199 (54 folders) (Carton 356)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Senate Bills from the 1975-1976 sessions, SB 1700-2172 (15 folders) (Box 357)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills from the 1975-1976 session, AB 901-4502 (42 folders) (Carton 355)
    - Mixed legislation; includes Assembly Bills from the 1979-1980 session, AB 1-499 (40 folders) (Carton 364)
    - Mixed legislation; includes notes and correspondence on Senate Bills, Senate Constitutional Amendments, Senate Resolutions, Assembly Bills, and general legislative correspondence (24 folders), 1978-1980 (Box 287)
    - Research; includes employment materials regarding civil rights, Proposition 10, and other related topics (33 folders), 1973-1976 (Carton 361)
    - Research; includes civil rights and voting rights legislation; record types include copies of bills, clippings, publications, and correspondence (28 folders), 1975-1976 (Carton 358)
    - Voting rights legislation; Ex-Felon Voting Rights (Proposition 10); includes voting pamphlets, census information, campaigning materials, committee information, voting records in the Senate and Assembly, prosecution statistics, press releases, notes, memorandums, correspndence; also includes related cases, Ramirez v. Brown, Richardson v. Ramirez (32 folders), 1964-1974 (Carton 382)
  - Series 3. Litigation
    - California Agrarian Action Project (CAAP) v. UC Regents; includes pleadings; also reports, policy research, clippings, articles, correspondence (24 folders), 1977-1981 (Carton 195)
    - California Agrarian Action Project (CAAP) v. UC Regents, plaintiffs' exhibits; includes exhibits 256, 257, 345-569, and volume one and two of the status of proof (22 folders) (Carton 291)
    - California Agrarian Action Project (CAAP) v. UC Regents, plaintiffs' exhibits 1100-1373.2, 1400-1480.83, 1600-1697, 1700-2521, 2700-3825 (16 folders) (Carton 292)
    - California Agrarian Action Project (CAAP) v. UC Regents; pleadings, transcripts, exhibits (34 folders), circa 1985 (Carton 42)
    - California Agrarian Action Project (CAAP) v. UC Regents; includes pleadings, transcripts, exhibits (10 folders), circa 1985 (Box 43)
    - CRLA litigation case summaries and docket notebooks (5 folders), 1967-1979 (Box 225)
    - CRLA v. Superior Court of California for the County of Santa Barbara; includes exhibits in support of petition, petition for writ of mandate, application for leave to file amicus curiae brief in support of petition (4 folders), 1992 (Box 339)
    - CRLA v. Superior Court of California for the County of Santa Barbara; includes Court of Appeals pleadings (5 folders), 1992-1994 (Box 338)
    - Castro v. California; pleadings (4 folders), circa 1968-1969 (Box 312)
    - Catholic Social Services (CSS) v. Meese (Barr), depositions; also includes exhibits used during the depositions and reporters' transcripts of judge's decision (23 folders), c. 1987-1992 (Carton 186)
    - Committee for Full Employment (CFE) v. Blumenthal, Secretary of Treasury; includes pleadings, opening brief, working file, clippings, as well as, notes, oral arguments, and research on revenue sharing (17 folders), c. 1977 (Box 297)
    - Education litgation: bilingual regulations and financing; including Mexican-American Council on Education v. Board of Education for United School District No. 457, Larry P. v. Riles, Office of the Sacramento County Superintendent od Schools v. State of California; includes preliminary statements, answers, orders, complaints, reports, news articles, correspondence (19 folders), 1978-1985 (Box 227)
    - Espindola v. Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS); pleadings; also Naranjo-Aguilera v. INS and Velasquez v. Ackerman (12 folders), 1992-1993 (Carton 317)
    - Exhibits for unidentified mechanization case (14 folders) (Carton 202)
    - Famous CRLA cases historical file; includes notes, cases summaries, and docket sheets on famous and compelling cases (8 folders), circa 1967-1988 (Box 313)
    - Furukawa Farms, Bill Hoerger's files regarding 1989 ALRB election hearing; includes Borrello flier information and event files; document types include: pleadings, memos and correspondence, research and discovery files, clippings, and publications (37 folders), c. 1988-1989 (Carton 369)
    - Furukawa Farms v. CRLA; includes Agricultural Labor Relations Board (ALRB) proceedings, payroll data, exhibits, interrogatories, depositions, motions, briefs, expert witness information, attorney notes and information, press releases, memos, correspondence (23 folders), 1987-1995 (Carton 331)
    - Furakawa Farms v. CRLA; includes contract agreements, exhibits and documents produced, depositions, correspondence (29 folders), 1988-1991 (Carton 337)
    - Furukawa Farms v. CRLA; includes depositions, exhibits, declarations, reporter's transcripts of proceedings, correspondence (27 folders), 1989-1991 (Carton 334)
    - Furukawa Farms v. CRLA; includes proceedings, exhibits and witness examinations; also witness files, hearing transcripts, interrogatories, growers contracts, notes; Superior Court pleadings and exhibits (21 folders), 1988-1991 (Carton 336)
    - Furukawa Farms v. CRLA; includes Superior Court pleadings and exhibits, bankruptcy proceedings, growers contract, correspondence (17 folders), 1988-1994 (Carton 333)
    - Furukawa Farms v. CRLA; includes Superior Court pleadings and exhibits (8 folders), 1990-1991 (Box 332)
    - Furukawa Farms v. CRLA; includes witness files, testimonies, hearing transcripts, interrogatories, notes, correspondence (10 folders), 1988-1990 (Box 335)
    - Pauline Gee files; primarily focused on education and immigrant labor; includes case summaries, case information, legal codes, Department of Education rules and regulations, correspndence, memos, reports, studies, newsletters, news articles, annual reports, notes (22 folders), 1968-1998 (Carton 330)
    - Gonzalez v. Furukawa Farms; includes complaints and amended complaints, motions, requests for documents, arbitration documents, depositions, exhibits, Joint Appendix on Class Certification Appeal (21 folders), 1987-1992 (Carton 222)
    - Gonzalez v. Furukawa Farms; includes defendant's interrogatories, working drafts, research (7 folders), 1987-1992 (Box 223)
    - Gordon v. Justice Court of Yuba City; includes pleadings, research, notes, memos, legislation, and correspondence concerning the legality of non-attorneys serving on justice courts that hear criminal cases (25 folders) (Carton 301)
    - Hampton v. Wong; includes Supreme Court, ninth circuit documents, appellants reply briefs, brief of amici curiae, other briefs; also correspondence, research, pleadings, 1973-1974 (Box 58)
    - De Haro v. St. Helena (Calif.); includes discovery files (8 folders), 1993-1994 (Box 318)
      Closed until 2069
    - Immigration litigation; including International Molders Union v. Nelson (INS), Equal Rights Congress v. Nelson, United Farm Workers of America v. Nelson, including motions, briefs, summaries, opinions, orders, declarations, affidavits, research, correspondence, news articles; also includes Special Agricultural Workers (SAW) information, newsletters, correspondence (8 folders), 1978-1993 (Box 226)
    - International Human Rights files; includes petitions to Inter-American Commission on Human Rights (IACHR) Organization of American States (OAR) and UN High Commissioner, human rights files involving Amnesty International, International Human Rights Law Group (IHRLG), National Council of Churches, Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights, International Human Rights Bill/Treaty; Central Valley Equal Rights Coucil (CVERC) v US including related research and news articles relating to immigrant drowning deaths, also includes exhibits, investigation reports, press releases (14 folders), 1979-1992 (Carton 224)
    - Kievlan v. Dahlberg/ Kievlan v. Maier; includes pleadings, correspondence, and court documents; the case concerns a group of senior citizens suing Dahlberg Electronics over false advertising for hearing aids (11 folders) (Carton 108)
    - Legal research; topics include mechanization of agriculture and attorneys' fees (9 folders) (Box 110)
    - Lopez v. Davidian, correspondence; also includes research on related cases, research notes, and miscellaneous related records such as questionnaires for potential witnesses, and press clippings (9 folders), circa 1988-1994 (Box 181)
    - Lopez v. Davidian, pleadings; also includes extra copies of orders, briefs, and complaints as well as exhibits used at trial, circa 1988-1994 (Carton 182)
    - Lopez v. Davidian (Lopez v. Ezell); includes memos and correspondence and supporting documents relating to the defendants and plaintiffs: records of deportable aliens, INS reports, and temporary worker identification card copies (8 folders), circa 1989-1990 (Box 180)
      Closed Until 2065
    - Lopez v. Ezell (Davidian), depositions; includes copies of depositions, exhibits presented in support, and reporters' transcripts (13 folders), 1989-1990 (Box 183)
    - MAPA v. Honig; includes pleadings for original case, appeal, summary judgment, and settlement, as well as exhibits and depositions (16 folders), 1985-1991 (Carton 87)
    - MAPA v. Honig; includes correspondence, notes and drafts, and research and discovery (25 folders), 1985-1991 (Carton 88)
    - MAPA v. Honig; includes research and discovery, publicity, and other materials related to the case (10 folders), 1985-1991 (Box 89)